Xin Jin

M3052, 3/F, Run Run Shaw Creative Media Centre, 18 Tat Hong Avenue, Kowloon Tong, Hong Kong

E-mail: xin.jin@cityu.edu.hk Tel: (+852)57499397

Profile

The research I have done before including popular culture, media and gender, and ideology analysis. Now I focus on computational social science, political communication, and data mining-processing-visualization. Meanwhile, I am also interested in creative media and proficient in many types of video producing, especially in documentary, creative microfilm, interview and news comment. I have a strong desire to try new things in both research and practice.

Education

City University of Hong Kong

M.A. in Communication and New Media-Media Data Analytics Stream Sep 2018 - Present

Fudan University Shanghai, China

F.I.S.T. Summer School in Quantitative Communication Research Method Jul 2018

Jinan University & Northwestern University & BBC

Guangzhou, Guangdong, China Jul 2015

Central South University

"Media Leaders" Summer School

Changsha, Hunan, China

Sep 2014 - Jun 2018

Hong Kong, China

B.A. (with honors) in Radio and Television

Research

Research Experience

Research Assistant Jan 2019 – Present

(Prof. Fen Lin, Dept Media & Communication, City U, Project#9042463)

- Mainly focus on International Communication using computational social science method
- The Comparison of "Tibet" in People's Daily, The New York Times, and Social Media Based on Topic Modeling
- How Chinese and Canadian Media Frame the Meng Wanzhou Affair
- The Change of News Coverage of "Tian'an men", "The Berlin Wall", "Umbrella Movement" and "Hitler" in Global Mainstream Media

Research Intern Sep 2018 – Present

(Prof. Jonathan J. H. Zhu, Web Mining Lab, Dept Media & Communication, City U)

- Online web data mining, data processing and calculating
- Student leader of project The Rank of Communication Discipline Around the Word
- The Comparison of Computational Communication Research and Non-computational Communication Research Based on TF-IDF Method

Xin Jin

Project

The Mechanism of How Self-media Influences People's Cognition and Code of Conduct

(National-level S.R.T.P. Fund, Project#201610533241, 10,000 CNY)

Mar 2017

- Leader
- Research method and questionnaire designing, ideology and myth analysis
- Award for Excellent Academic Innovation Project
- Award for Excellent Academic Innovation Paper

Analysis of Web Texts of Social Hot Events

Jun 2017

(Provincial Social Science Foundation of China)

- Participant of instructor's project (Dr. Huang)
- Leader of "Wei Zexi event" text analysis group
- Analysis of dominant reading

Study of Violent Narration in Current Popular Culture

Aug 2017

(Provincial Social Science Foundation of China)

- Participant of instructor's project (Dr. Huang)
- Semiotic analysis of language violence, behavior violence and environment violence of 10 popular movies

Conference

<u>Jin, X.</u>, Ye, Q. Y. (05/01/2019). Impact of Different Social Media Context on Attitude Polarization of Hot Topic Online. *The 1st CUC Ph.D Students Academic Forum on New Media*, Communication University of China, Beijing, China.

Professional Achievement

You Young New Media Studio

Mar 2018

(National-level S.E.T.P. Fund, Project#201810533586, 10,000 CNY)

- Leader & Founder
- Award for Excellent Entrepreneurship Practice Project
- Second Award in "Shenghua Cup" Competition of Science and Technology (Cultural and Creative Industry Track)

Film Works

National College Students' Sports Micro Film Contest

Top 10 prize-Zero Distance with Rio Olympic Champions

National Cross-strait College Students Visual Works Exhibition

1st prize-Days of Being Sorrowful (Cantonese)

National Medical Health Science Micro Video Contest

Grand prize-How to Dress Correctly for Newborns

Hunan Radio & Television Program Contest, Hunan Satellite TV

3rd prize-*Changsha on the Fingertip*

Xin Jin

The 5th Hunan College Student Art Exhibition

3rd prize-Talk to Myself (Cantonese)

Hunan TV & Radio College Association TV Program Contest

1st prize-Seniors Speaking from the Bottom of the Heart 2nd prize-Long Drum from the Distant Mountain 3rd prize-the Battle in Millimeters (Hand-made Contest of Clinical Medical Students)

Honors and Awards

Distinction Bachelor Graduate Award, Central South UniversityJun 2018National Scholarship (#201714297), Ministry of Education of P.R.CNov 2017Excellent Academic Innovation Individual, Office of Innovation of CSUMay 2017Second-class Scholarship, Central South UniversityNov 2015, 2016

Skills

Python-Skilled,Excel-Skilled,Power Point-Proficient,Word-ProficientWord-Proficient

Links

Media Data Driven Works

Predicting the Taiwan City / County Level Councilor Election Result Based on The Topic of Election Promise http://t.cn/Ea2NCkI

THE DISEASED WORLD-An Overview of Global Disease Outbreak (1996-2018) http://t.cn/EbRKEhP

Topic Modeling of "Tibet" in People's Daily http://t.cn/EIxhy2B

Multiple methods of visualization of Gapminder http://t.cn/EbRKkNJ

The Rank of Communication Discipline Around the World http://t.cn/EctFLHi http://t.cn/EbR9GSB

The Change of News Coverage of "Tian'an men", "The Berlin Wall", "Umbrella Movement" and "Hitler" in Global Mainstream Media https://xjincomm.wixsite.com/intcomm

· About Me

Personal Website https://xjincomm.wixsite.com/xjin

CityU Staff Profile Page http://www6.cityu.edu.hk/stfprofile/xin.jin.htm

LinkedIn https://www.linkedin.com/in/xjin613

You Young Creative Media Studio https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCoKxYZjMWNfthjj211gJSKQ